Register of the Joseph Hansen Papers, 1887-1980.
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1887-1978
  - Great Britain. Pamphlets, serial issues, printed articles, clippings, and newsletters. Includes some Communist Party of Great Britain issuances
    - 1938-1963 (Folder 3)
    - 1964-1967 (Folder 4)
    - 1968-1977 (Folder 5)
  - Greece. Pamphlet, 1944 (Folder 6)
  - Guatemala
    - General. Printed articles and clippings, 1953-1967 (Folder 7)
    - Rosen, Bernard, "El Desarrollo del Imperialismo en Guatemala, 1870-1920: Estudio Historico-Politico," 1953 (Folder 8)
  - Haywood, William D. Memorandum by F. G. Clarke, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Indonesia. Printed articles, 1966-1969 (Folder 10)
  - Internal security--United States. Pamphlet, printed articles, clippings, Congressional hearing transcripts, and text of Internal Security Act, 1940-1969 (Folder 11)
  - Jamaica. Pamphlet, printed article, and clippings, 1961 (Folder 12)
  - Japan. Pamphlets and clippings, 1938-1941. Includes printed text of Tanaka Memorial (Folder 13)
  - Kennedy, John F.--Assassination. Pamphlet and printed articles, 1964 (Folder 14)
  - Krivitsky, Walter G. Printed articles and clippings, 1939-1941 (Folder 15)
  - Latin America. Serial issues, printed articles, clippings, bulletins, and newsletters
    - 1952-1960 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - 1961 (Folder 2)
    - 1962-1969 (Folder 3)
  - Lysenko, Trofim. Pamphlet, printed articles, and clippings, 1944-1949 (Folder 4)
  - Mexico
    - General. Pamphlets, serial issues, printed articles, clippings, and leaflets
      - 1937-1962 (Folder 5)
      - 1966-1971 (Folder 6)
    - Programa issues, 1952-1953 (Folder 7)
  - Mills, C. Wright. Printed articles and leaflet, 1956-1961 (Folder 8)
  - Miscellany. Printed matter and typescript article, 1887-1977. Includes photocopy of first edition of pamphlet by Friedrich Engels, Die Arbeiterbewegung in Amerika (Folder 9)
  - Nicaragua. Frente Sandinista de Liberacion Nacional communique, 1974 (Folder 10)
  - Organizacion Latinoamericana de Solidaridad. Speech, statement, leaflets, program, and miscellany, 1966-1967. Includes program of, and greetings of Bertrand Russell to, 1967 conference in Havana (Folder 11)
  - Peru. Printed articles, clippings, and printed texts of legislation
    - 1956-1961 (Folder 12)
    - 1962 (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - 1964-1969 (Folder 2)
    - 1970-1974 (Folder 3)
  - Philippines. Serial issues, printed articles, clippings, and leaflets, 1941-1971. Includes issuances of Communist Party of the Philippines (Folder 4)
  - Poland. Printed articles and clipping, 1949-1966 (Folder 5)
  - Population
    - General. Pamphlets, serial issues, printed articles, bulletins, and newsletters
      - 1943-1959 (Folder 6)
      - 1960 (Folder 7)
      - 1960-1962 (Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1954-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Portugal. Printed article, 1975 (Folder 10)
  - Presidents--United States--Election-- 1952. Serial issues (mainly issued by trade unions), 1952 (Folder 11)
  - Puerto Rico. Printed article, clippings, leaflet, and program of Puerto Rican Socialist Party, 1960-1971 (Folder 12)
  - Rivera, Diego. Printed article and clippings, 1940-1957 (Folder 13)
  - Schoenman, Ralph. Memoranda, leaflet, and clippings, 1966-1970. Includes writings by Schoenman (Folder 14)
  - Science. Printed articles and clippings
    - 1940-1946 (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - 1947-1948 (Folder 2)
    - 1949-1960 (Folder 3)
  - Soviet Union. Serial issues, printed articles, clippings, and bulletins, 1936-1967 (Folder 4)
  - Spain. Pamphlet, serial issue, printed article, and clippings, 1937-1965 (Folder 5)
  - Sri Lanka. Photocopies of parliamentary documents, and clipping, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - Technocracy. Serial issues, 1934-1962 (Folder 7)
  - Trade-unions
    - General. Printed article, clippings, other printed matter, and leaflets, 1935-1962 (Folder 8)
    - Merchant seamen. Mimeograph log of negotiation sessions, serial issue, and other printed matter, 1936-1942 (Folder 9)
  - Uruguay. Pamphlet, serial issues, printed articles, and clippings, 1961-1972 (Folder 10)
  - Venezuela. Serial issue, printed articles, and clippings, 1961-1962 (Folder 11)
  - Vietnam. Serial issues, printed articles, clippings, leaflets, and mimeograph documents, 1967-1971. Includes appeal by Bertrand Russell for institution of an International War Crimes Tribunal, and findings of the Tribunal (Folder 12)
  - War. Printed articles and clippings, 1936-1964 (Folder 13)
  - Yugoslavia. Pamphlet, printed article, and clippings, 1935-1964 (Folder 14)
  - Zborowski, Mark. Printed articles and clippings, 1955-1958 (Folder 15)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1976-1977.
  - Large format Security and the Fourth International series publications, reprinting articles from Workers Revolutionary Party (Great Britain) press. See also FOURTH INTERNATIONAL FILE/Great Britain/Socialist Labour League/Workers Revolutionary Party subject file/Accusation campaign (Box 105)
- INDEXES.
  - Partial indexes prepared by Library of Social History, 1983-1984, to writings by Joseph Hansen in Joseph Hansen Papers, prior to present arrangement of collection. To correlate former locations listed in indexes with present locations, check data field TYP[e], which appears in every index. If TYP is coded L (for letter), turn to Letters Index and locate desired item alphabetically under name appearing in ADDRESSEE data field. All items in Letters Index are annotated to indicate box and folder number of present location. If TYP is not coded L, turn to Chronological Index and locate desired item chronologically under date appearing in ITEM# data field. All items in Chronological Index except those coded L are annotated to indicate box and folder number of present location. Note: Indexes do not include all writings or letters by Hansen (Box 106)
  - Table of Contents of former arrangement
  - Chronological Index
  - Letters Index
  - Fourth International/Socialist Workers Party Meetings Index
  - Country Index
  - Subject Index
  - Worksheets used in preparation of Indexes (Box 107-108)
  - Worksheets used in preparation of Indexes (Box 109)
  - Preliminary list of Latin American materials
- PHONOTAPE, 1977.
  - Sound recording of speeches by Joseph Hansen and Greco before central committee of Partido Socialista de los Trabajadores (Colombia), 1977 December 9. See also SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Notes and speech, 1977 November 27-December 11 (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, ca. 1900-1975.
  - 58 prints of Joseph Hansen, family members, and acquaintances. See Photo Card Catalog (Photo-cabinet 10-A.V.)
- INCREMENT, 1927-1972. (Box 110)
  - Biographical File
    - Latter Day Saints University yearbook, 1927 (Box-folder 110:1)
  - Speeches and Writings
    - Father Coughlin: Fascist Demagogue (pamphlet), 1939 (Box-folder 110:2)
      Printed copy
    - Wall Street's War, Not Ours! (pamphlet), 1940 (Box-folder 110:3)
    - American Workers Need a Labor Party (pamphlet), 1944 (Box-folder 110:4)
    - The Socialist Workers Party: What It Is, What It Stands For (pamphlet), 1948 (Box-folder 110:5)
    - Too Many Babies? (pamphlet), 1960 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - In Defense of the Cuban Revolution: An Answer to the State Department and Theodore Draper (pamphlet), 1961 (Box-folder 110:7)
    - Healy "Reconstructs" the Fourth International: Documents and Comments by Participants in a Fiasco (editor; pamphlet), 1966 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - Murder in Memphis: Martin Luther King and the Future of the Black Liberation Struggle (co-author; pamphlet), 1968 (Box-folder 110:9)
    - The Invasion of Czechoslovakia (co-author; pamphlet), 1969 (Box-folder 110:10)
    - Nixon's Moscow and Peking Summits: Their Meaning for Vietnam (co-author with Caroline Lund; pamphlet), 1972 (Box-folder 110:11)
    - A Revolutionary Strategy for the 70s: Documents of the Socialist Workers Party (co-author), 1972 (Box-folder 110:12)